## Hassan Abrar

Address: Rawalpindi

**Contact:** +923330979197

Email: Hassan.abrar@iotascale.io

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/hassan-abrar-494229142/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/hassan-abrar-494229142/</a>

**GitHub:** <a href="https://github.com/HassanAbrar97">https://github.com/HassanAbrar97</a>

#### **Professional Profile:**

I'm enthusiastic in innovation of Web App industry across all platform especially Node Application development, Currently I'm working as a backend developer at lotascale where my skills can be used to create future Apps. My primary goal at the moment is to gain experience and learn more about emerging technologies.

## **Education Qualification:**

**➤ Islamic University –** (2016-2020)

Degree subject - BSSE

- ✓ The major subjects I studied are OOP, Databases, Software constructions and Networking.
- ✓ The **'Final Year Project'** I did was Twitter Sentiment Analysis. Through which you can check sentiment analysis by using different hashtags
- **→ Harvard College −** (2014-2016)

Degree subject - Inter in Computer Sciences.

➤ Senior Sir Syed School – (2012-2014)

**Degree subject** – Matric in Science.

# **Experience:**

➤ **Iotascale** – Backend Developer

June 2022 - Current

Meridian Software Technology Park – Oracle DB Manager

(Nov 2021 – May 2022)

> Bitnbytes Tech - Intern

(Aug 2021 – Oct 2021)

8-week internship as DB manager

# **Project:**

# Monitoring System, ERPNext, Power BI dashboard

## > Twitter Sentiment Analysis

Developed a Web Application for Twitter Sentiment Analysis. We used React, Node.js, MongoDB and Kafka for big data management.

### Easy Chat

A real time chatting application on which you can create your profile, chat with your friends, update status, Like or Comment, you can Follow your friend or get followed and you can get notifications (Built using Angular, Node.js).

### Cinema Ticketing

A desktop application on which you can generate tickets on required date and manage your cinema (Built using Java).

## **Skills:**

- > Linux
- ➢ Git

### Languages

- ➤ Node.js
- Express.js
- JavaScript
- > TypeScript
- > Angular
- Python
- ➤ HTML5/CSS3

#### **Databases**

- Clickhouse
- ➤ MongoDB
- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- > Firebase
- > Redis

#### **DevOps**

- VMware
- Google Cloud Services
- Serverless
- Docker / Containers
- Jenkins
- OPManager usage + APIs / Zabbix